Preliminary Inventory to the Lewis, Roger L. Papers, 1917-1919
Hoover Institution Archives
Lewis, Roger L. Papers,
1917-1919
64004
Lewis, Roger L., d. 1936
1 manuscript box, 1 envelope. (0.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, notes, correspondence, printed matter, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to operations of the American Red Cross in Archangel, Russia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
American National Red Cross.; International relief.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
List of papers, pictures etc. belonging to Roger L. Lewis, (deceased 1936) Associated Press correspondent, Editor of The American Sentinel. Captain in Red Cross 1919.
- Russian Daily News (English) 31 Aug 1917
- Russian Newspapers (in Russian) 1918., 7 copies
- The Chicago Tribune (Paris Edition) Aug 14, 1919
- The American Sentinel-Archangel, Russia
  Issues of March 8, 1919, April 5, 1919.
- G.A.F. The Gazette of the Archangel Force (English)
  Issues of June 7 (2) and June 14, 1919.
- The Hatchet, Tuesday, August 19, 1919
- Thanksgiving Proclamation by Pres. Woodrow Wilson Published in Archangel, Nov. 25, 1918.
- Letter from Embassy of the U.S.A. thanking Capt. Roger L. Lewis, A.R.C. for his work in publishing The American Sentinel.
- Carbon copy of report of work of Red Cross, perhaps that referred to in above letter. (pages missing)
- Letter from Brig. Genrl W.P. Richardson in thanks for The American Sentinel.
- Report on trip to Railroad Front-April 30th, 1919 Lt. Fred Mason, A.R.C.
- American Red Cross Mission to Russia-General Order No. 3 Sept. 23, 1918.
- Safe conduct pass from Embas sy issued to Roger L. Lewis as special messenger. Oct. 13, 1917.
- 4 pages from notebook penciled by Roger L. Lewis (Kerensky is mentioned a number of times)
- Letter to Roger Lewis from Geroge Creek, Dec. 22, 1917. (Committee on Public Information)
- 6 papers in Russian Contents???
  11 Newspaper clippings. One telling of capture of Roger Lewis of the Associated Press; Irvin S. Cobb the Saturday Evening Post and the Philadelphia Public Ledger. James O'Donnell Bennett and John T. McCutcheon, the Chicago Tribune, and Harry Hansen, the Chicago Daily News.
- 30 Various photographs- some photographed by American Red Cross
  - 4 in offices of The American Sentinel
  - Ambassador Francis of the U.S.A. Pres. N.W. Tchoykovsky
  - Group of Ambassadors-including Francis
  - Red Cross groups. Street scenes in Archangel etc.
  - Some not identified.